baltimorecity.gov 2004-12-05

# BaltimoreCity.gov: Privacy Statement

### Privacy Statement 

The City of Baltimore and its subsidiaries are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. The Web site is structured so that you can visit the City of Baltimore on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information.

Once you choose to provide personally identifiable information (any information by which you can be identified), you can be assured that it will only be used for the intended purposes. 

This statement regarding the privacy of the personally identifiable information you provide online covers the four foundation principles of fair information: Awareness, Access, Security, and Oversight. 

#### Awareness 

The City of Baltimore provides this Online Privacy Statement to make you aware of the privacy policy, practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, it is available on the homepage.

#### What information is collected?

On some City of Baltimore pages, you can submit personal information through forms or via e-mail links. The types of personal information collected at these pages.

In order to tailor subsequent communications to you and continuously improve services, you may also be asked you to provide information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with city services and more detailed contact preferences. 

#### How will this information be used? 

The City of Baltimore uses your information to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, your information is used to communicate back to you, to update you on services and benefits and personalize the City Web site for you. 

#### Will this information be shared?

The City of Baltimore will not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to others. Unless required by law, the city will only share the personal data you provide online with other City of Baltimore entities and/or business partners who are acting on behalf of the city for the uses described in "How will this information be used?". Such entities and/or business partners are governed by privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality agreements. 

#### Access 

Links to third party Web sites on the site are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the the City of Baltimore site. The City of Baltimore has not reviewed all of these third party sites and does not control or is not responsible for any of these sites, their content or their privacy policy. Thus, the City of Baltimore does not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or products or materials found there. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to this site, you do so at your own risk. 

#### Security 

The City of Baltimore is committed to ensuring the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures have been put into place to safeguard and secure the information collected online. 

Furthermore, this site takes reasonable measures to maintain the confidentiality of all personal information collectedl. Additionally, it takes similar measures to protect email addresses that you provide through the website.

#### Oversight 

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please e-mail the site's administrator at [webmaster@baltimorecity.gov](mailto:webmaster@baltimorecity.gov).

Home Page • Terms of Use
